<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Shift Happens</title><link>https://blog.arunmalik.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Shift Happens</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.arunmalik.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azure Data Factory: Simplifying Data Integration and Transformation</title><link>https://blog.arunmalik.dev/posts/twominread/adf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.arunmalik.dev/posts/twominread/adf/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="getting-started-with-azure-data-factory-orchestrating-your-data-workflows">&lt;strong>Getting Started with Azure Data Factory: Orchestrating Your Data Workflows&lt;/strong>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In today’s data-driven world, organizations need a robust solution to efficiently move and transform data across different systems and environments. &lt;strong>Azure Data Factory (ADF)&lt;/strong> is a fully managed cloud-based ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) service that helps you integrate, transform, and load data from multiple sources to a centralized data store like Azure SQL, Azure Blob Storage, or even external services like Amazon S3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Zero Trust in Azure: Because Trust is Overrated</title><link>https://blog.arunmalik.dev/posts/zerotrust/zerotrust/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.arunmalik.dev/posts/zerotrust/zerotrust/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="zero-trust-in-azure-because-trust-is-overrated">Zero Trust in Azure: Because Trust is Overrated&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In today’s digital world, securing your cloud environment is crucial, and a &lt;strong>Zero Trust&lt;/strong> approach is one of the best ways to protect against unauthorized access and potential breaches. When implementing Zero Trust in &lt;strong>Azure&lt;/strong>, there are several strategies that can help secure your network and ensure that every request, connection, and user is continuously verified. Here’s a breakdown of key strategies to secure your Azure environment using &lt;strong>Zero Trust&lt;/strong> principles.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>